Hi it's Dow here at the Firehouse Detail Center, today we're detailing the exterior of your car and we're teaching you how to be an expert at doing it as well.
In a previous segment we applied wax.
We talked about the selection of wax and picking the wax that's best for you.
An important part of waxing the car is actually the removal of the wax.
We want to use the right equipment to remove it, and we want to make sure we remove wax in the crevices and cracks.
So we don't want to fly through this too fast because you'll have a disappointed customer or you'll be disappointed at the look of your vehicle if you've got excess wax.
So be cautious not to put too much wax to begin with.
One of the common problems we have is people use too much wax.
You just don't need a ton, a tremendous amount of product.
A little bit of wax goes a long ways.
Once its been hazed over and its had a chance to dry then we want to circle back using a microfiber towel, and again have several towels, turn it frequently, use a clean area of the towel to remove it.
You're going to want to remove it the same direction you put it on which is the way that the wind flows over the car back and forth.
We're going to go back and forth covering new areas, again flipping my towel frequently, so that I've got a fresh new area as I go over it.
Now when I hit an area like this detail trim here where the headlight is.
If I've got wax in there I can get a detail brush to go through and remove wax.
I can even, you know, wrap a towel in it and go into the crevices, or fold a towel if I've got a bumper line like that I can fold the towel and just press it along the crevice like that.
When it comes out it's gone in and it's removed any excess wax. You can move through the car wax removal pretty quickly, but pay attention to details because when you have too much wax in a crevice that's an area that's going to make your customer disappointed and you're not going to like the way it looks on your own vehicle if you're a do it yourselfer.
With that, the microfiber towel will leave a nice shine and the paint finish is going to be just perfect for ninety to one hundred and twenty days.
You can go back and reapply wax more often than that, but we find that our customers are delighted for at least ninety or one hundred and twenty days.